Dedicated and resourceful Shopify Developer, offering a proven track record of success in the eCommerce industry with extensive experience in developing and scaling online stores. Strong background in working remotely, skilled with HTML, CSS, Liquid, JavaScript, and various APIs. Previously, I successfully navigated the world of freelancing, accumulating a diverse client base and gaining valuable lessons along the way.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ECOM DEPT Apr. 2023 – Present

Shopify Developer

Los Angeles, CA (Remote)

- 3-person dev team inside of a full-service ecommerce agency
- some legacy Shopify build maintenance (Slate v1, webpack etc)
- piloting multiple full builds by myself (using OS 2.0, in-house proprietary theme, git workflow etc)
- helped with development of proprietary theme that is used for all of our clients, helping with development of proprietary backend portal for clients

Acadaca Mar. 2022 – Apr. 2023

Shopify Developer

Brooklyn, New York (Remote)

- 60-person boutique ecommerce agency with a broad spectrum of clients including fashion, beauty, lifestyle, etc
- As one of the few Shopify Developer's on the team, I was responsible for:
 - o implementing new features, debugging existing features, supporting other team members
 - o HTML, CSS, Liquid, Javascript, APIs, Git, many 3rd-party shopify apps
- Contributed to over 50+ Shopify Plus merchants, including building out many features and stores by myself
- Some feature examples include age gates, engraving modals, custom checkout flows, outfit builders, and more

eComAllies Nov. 2019 – Mar. 2021

Shopify Developer

Austin, TX (Remote)

- eCommerce agency focused on rapidly growing Shopify startup brands, including food, beauty, lifestyle, etc
- As the only developer (when hired), I was initially contracted as a freelancer and tasked with debugging tracking codes and pixels, as this was strictly an ad agency and did not focus on dev work.
- After a year or so, clients began demanding more dev-related work, and I was offered to come on full-time and ultimately was the one responsible for implementing small custom features to already existing Shopify stores.

Freelance May 2014 - Nov. 2020

Shopify Developer, Web Developer

Cincinnati, OH (Remote)

- Sole proprietor for 5+ years handling all devops, sales, accounting, customer service, admin, etc.
- Serviced over 75+ clients small and large. eCommerce sites, static sites, and unique projects.
- Roster of happy and satisfied clients, list of failures & lessons learned along the way.

EDUCATION

N/A

- High school diploma
- Online coursework including Udemy, Freecodecamp, Sololearn, Shopify's Partner training, Shopify Workshops

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- **Skills:** Shopify Plus, OS 2.0, eCommerce, Javascript, Liquid, UI Design, Typography, React, Node, Command Line, Git, Server Management, Troubleshooting/Debugging, Time Tracking
- Interests: Playing and producing music, learning about nature, puzzle games, chess, being an introvert

Previous Work Examples (Shopify Plus)

These are previous projects/clients that I've contributed heavily to. My work history with these projects is documented in my Github commit history (https://github.com/jclarkdev)

- Full Builds

- Womaness (https://womaness.com)
- Amiri (https://amiri.com)
- HOBO Bags (https://hobobags.com/)
- XSET (https://shopxset.com/)
- Motherhood Maternity (https://motherhood.com/)
- Nolah Mattress (https://nolahmattress.com/)
- The Macallan U.S. (https://themacallan.com/)
- BCBG (https://bcbg.com)
- Bodyglove (https://bodyglove.com/)
- Corpus Naturals (https://corpusnaturals.com)
- Alicia Dakteris (https://aliciadakteris.com/)
- ... and many more!

- Features/components

- Custom apparel sizing app (https://bensherman.com/pages/quiz)
- Pore Clogger Checker App (https://www.bibalosangeles.com/pages/pore-clogger-checker)
- Age gate w/ cookies (https://usshop.themacallan.com)
- Fully customized checkout flow (https://usshop.themacallan.com)
- Fully custom PDP (https://www.hobobags.com/collections/leather-satchel-handbags)
- Custom search results and filtering (https://thelaundress.com/search)
- ... and many more!